<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>women's health</term>
  <file>viv_MRt30J</file>
  <server>pvlb7srch15</server>
  <count>335</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="335" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="0" url="https://medlineplus.gov/womenshealth.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; have unique &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; issues. And some of the &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; issues that affect both men and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; can affect &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; differently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unique issues include pregnancy, menopause, and conditions of the female organs. &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; can have a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;healthy&lt;/span&gt; pregnancy by getting early and regular prenatal care. They should also get recommended breast cancer, cervical cancer, and bone density screenings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; and men also have many of the same &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; problems. But these problems can affect &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; differently. For example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; are more likely to die following a heart attack than men&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; are more likely to show signs of depression and anxiety than men&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The effects of sexually transmitted infections (STIs) can be more serious in &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Osteoarthritis affects more &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; than men&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; are more likely to have urinary tract problems&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Child &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Development&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Population Groups</content>
      <content name="snippet"> &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; have unique &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; issues. And some of the &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; issues that affect both men and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; can affect &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; differently. Unique issues include pregnancy,  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="1" url="https://medlineplus.gov/womenshealthcheckup.html">
      <content name="title">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; Checkup</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Pelvic Exam</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Regular checkups with your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider are different from appointments for sickness or injury. Your checkups, which are also called well-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; exams, include physical exams as well as preventive care. They can help find &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; problems early, when they may be easier to treat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your checkup will include screenings for chronic diseases. As a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt;, you may also get special exams and screenings, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A pelvic exam to check the &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; of your reproductive organs. The provider will look at your vulva, vagina, and cervix. They will also do an internal exam to feel the size and shape of your internal organs such as the uterus and ovaries.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A cervical cancer screening, which uses a Pap test, an HPV test, or both. The tests can help prevent cervical cancer. A Pap test checks for cervical cancer and for abnormal cells that could turn into cancer. An HPV test looks for the types of HPV which can cause cervical cancer. For both tests, your provider will take a sample of cells from the surface of your cervix and send them to a lab to be examined under a microscope.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A clinical breast exam to check for breast cancer. The provider will feel and look at your breasts and armpit area for lumps or other changes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which tests you get and how often you need them will depend on your age, overall &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt;, and family &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; history. In some cases, your provider may also recommend other tests as well. For example, if you have a family history of certain cancers, your provider may recommend genetic testing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During your checkup, you and your provider may also talk about other issues, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Birth control or family planning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Menopause&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Menstrual concerns&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sexually transmitted infections (STIs)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Vaccines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your overall &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt;, including suggestions on how to have a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;healthy&lt;/span&gt; lifestyle&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make the most of your next checkup, bring a list of any questions or concerns you have, so you can talk about them with your provider.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Physical Examination</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Wellness&lt;/span&gt; and Lifestyle</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Regular checkups with your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider are different from appointments for sickness or injury. Your checkups, which are also called well-&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; exams,  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="2" url="https://medlineplus.gov/hysterectomy.html">
      <content name="title">Hysterectomy</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;A hysterectomy is surgery to remove a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt;'s uterus or womb. The uterus is the place where a baby grows when a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; is pregnant.  After a hysterectomy, you no longer have menstrual periods and can't become pregnant.  Sometimes the surgery also removes the ovaries and fallopian tubes. If you have both ovaries taken out, you will enter menopause.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider might recommend a hysterectomy if you have:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fibroids&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Endometriosis that hasn't been cured by medicine or surgery&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uterine prolapse -  when the uterus drops into the vagina &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cancer of the uterine, cervix, or ovaries&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Vaginal bleeding that persists despite treatment  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chronic pelvic pain, as a last resort &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Hysterectomy</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Surgery and Rehabilitation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Female Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... pelvic pain , as a last resort   Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="https://medlineplus.gov/femaleinfertility.html">
      <content name="title">Female Infertility</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Infertility, Female</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Infertility means not being able to get pregnant after at least one year of trying (or 6 months if the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; is over age 35). If a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; keeps having miscarriages, it is also called infertility.  Female infertility can result from age, physical problems, hormone problems, and lifestyle or environmental factors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most cases of infertility in &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; result from problems with producing eggs. In primary ovarian insufficiency, the ovaries stop functioning before natural menopause.  In polycystic ovary syndrome (PCOS), the ovaries may not release an egg regularly or they may not release a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;healthy&lt;/span&gt; egg.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;About a third of the time, infertility is because of a problem with the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt;. One third of the time, it is a problem with the man. Sometimes no cause can be found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think you might be infertile, see your doctor. There are tests that may tell if you have fertility problems. When it is possible to find the cause, treatments may include medicines, surgery, or assisted reproductive technologies. Happily, many couples treated for infertility are able to have babies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Infertility, Female</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Pregnancy and Reproduction</content>
      <content name="groupName">Female Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    </document>
    <document rank="4" url="https://medlineplus.gov/prenatalcare.html">
      <content name="title">Prenatal Care</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Prenatal care is the &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care you get while you are pregnant. It includes your checkups and prenatal testing.  
Prenatal care can help keep you and your baby &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;healthy&lt;/span&gt;. It lets your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider spot &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; problems early. Early treatment can cure many problems and prevent others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your doctor or midwife will give you a schedule for your prenatal visits. If you are over 35 years old or your pregnancy is high risk because of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; problems like diabetes or high blood pressure, your doctor or midwife will probably want to see you more often. You can also expect to see your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider more often as your due date gets closer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Prenatal Care</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Pregnancy and Reproduction</content>
      <content name="groupName">Female Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... as your due date gets closer. Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    </document>
    <document rank="5" url="https://medlineplus.gov/premenstrualsyndrome.html">
      <content name="title">Premenstrual Syndrome</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">PMS</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is premenstrual syndrome (PMS)?&lt;p&gt;Premenstrual syndrome, or PMS, is a group of physical and emotional symptoms that start one to two weeks before your period. Most &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; have at least some symptoms of PMS, and the symptoms go away after their periods start. The symptoms may range from mild to severe.&lt;/p&gt;What is premenstrual dysphoric disorder (PMDD)?&lt;p&gt;Premenstrual dysphoric disorder (PMDD) is a severe type of PMS. With PMDD, the symptoms are severe enough to interfere with your life.  PMDD much less common than PMS.&lt;/p&gt;What causes premenstrual syndrome (PMS)?&lt;p&gt;Researchers don't know exactly what causes PMS. Changes in hormone levels during the menstrual cycle may play a role. These changing hormone levels may affect some &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; more than others.&lt;/p&gt;What are the symptoms of premenstrual syndrome (PMS)?&lt;p&gt;PMS symptoms are different for everyone. You may get physical symptoms, emotional symptoms, or both. Your symptoms may also change throughout your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Physical symptoms may include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breast swelling and tenderness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acne&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bloating and weight gain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Headache&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Joint pain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Backache&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Constipation or diarrhea&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Food cravings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emotional symptoms may include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Irritability&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mood swings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Crying spells&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Depression&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anxiety&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sleeping too much or too little&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trouble with concentration and memory&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Less interest in sex&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;How is premenstrual syndrome (PMS) diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;You may wish to see your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider if your symptoms bother you or affect your daily life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no single test for PMS. Your provider will talk with you about your symptoms, including when they happen and how much they affect your life.  To be diagnosed with PMS, your symptoms must:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Happen in the five days before your period for at least three menstrual cycles in a row&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;End within four days after your period starts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep you from enjoying or doing some of your normal activities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your provider may wish to do tests to rule out other conditions which may cause similar symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;What are the treatments for premenstrual syndrome (PMS)?&lt;p&gt;No single PMS treatment works for everyone. If your symptoms are not severe, you may be able to manage them with: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Over-the-counter pain relievers such as ibuprofen, aspirin, or naproxen, to help ease cramps, headaches, backaches, and breast tenderness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting regular exercise&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting enough sleep&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;healthy&lt;/span&gt; foods&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Avoiding salt, caffeine, sugar, and alcohol in the two weeks before your period&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some studies have shown that certain vitamins may help with some symptoms of PMS. They include calcium and vitamin B6.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; take certain herbal supplements for PMS symptoms. But there is not enough evidence to prove that supplements are effective for PMS. Check with your provider before taking any vitamins or supplements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are not able to manage your PMS symptoms, your provider may suggest prescription medicines. These medicines may also be used to treat PMDD. They include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hormonal birth control, which may help with the physical symptoms of PMS. But sometimes they may make the emotional symptoms worse. You may need to try several different types of birth control before you find the right one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Antidepressants, such as selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs), which may help with emotional symptoms.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Diuretics ("water pills") to reduce symptoms of bloating and breast tenderness.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anti-anxiety medicine to ease symptoms of anxiety.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder</content>
      <content name="mesh">Premenstrual Syndrome</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Female Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    </document>
    <document rank="6" url="https://medlineplus.gov/sexualproblemsinwomen.html">
      <content name="title">Sexual Problems in &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Dyspareunia</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Female Circumcision</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Female Sexual Dysfunction</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Vaginismus</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;There are many problems that can keep a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; from enjoying sex. They include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lack of sexual desire &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Inability to become aroused&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lack of orgasm, or sexual climax&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Painful intercourse&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These problems may have physical or psychological causes. Physical causes may include conditions like diabetes, heart disease, nerve disorders, or hormone problems. Some drugs can also affect desire and function. Psychological causes may include work-related stress and anxiety. They may also include depression or concerns about marriage or relationship problems. For some &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt;, the problem results from past sexual trauma. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Occasional problems with sexual function are common. If problems last more than a few months or cause distress for you or your partner, you should see your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Vaginismus</content>
      <content name="mesh">Dyspareunia</content>
      <content name="mesh">Sexual Dysfunctions, Psychological</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Sexual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; Issues</content>
      <content name="groupName">Female Reproductive System</content>
      <content name="snippet"> There are many problems that can keep a &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;woman&lt;/span&gt; from enjoying sex. They include: Lack of sexual desire   Inability to become aroused  Lack of orgasm, or sexual  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="7" url="https://medlineplus.gov/collegehealth.html">
      <content name="title">College &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;College life involves excitement, along with new challenges, risks, and responsibilities. You are meeting new people, learning new things, and making your own decisions. It can sometimes be stressful.  You have to deal with pressures related to food, drink, appearance, drugs, and sexual activity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are steps you can take to stay &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;healthy&lt;/span&gt; and safe while you're in college:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eat a balanced diet&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get enough sleep&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get regular physical activity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Maintain your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; with checkups and vaccinations&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you decide to have sex, practice safe sex&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make smart choices about alcohol and drugs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get help if you are stressed or depressed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Universities</content>
      <content name="mesh">Students</content>
      <content name="groupName">Children and Teenagers</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Wellness&lt;/span&gt; and Lifestyle</content>
      <content name="snippet"> College life involves excitement, along with new challenges, risks, and responsibilities. You are meeting new people, learning new things, and making your own  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="8" url="https://medlineplus.gov/postpartumdepression.html">
      <content name="title">Postpartum Depression</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Baby Blues</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Post-pregnancy depression</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Many &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;women&lt;/span&gt; have the baby blues after childbirth. If you have the baby blues, you may have mood swings, feel sad, anxious or overwhelmed, have crying spells, lose your appetite, or have trouble sleeping. The baby blues most often go away within a few days or a week. The symptoms are not severe and do not need treatment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The symptoms of postpartum depression last longer and are more severe.   You may also feel hopeless and worthless and lose interest in the baby. You may have thoughts of hurting yourself or the baby. Very rarely, new mothers develop something even more serious. They may have hallucinations or try to hurt themselves or the baby. They need to get treatment right away, often in the hospital.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Postpartum depression can begin anytime within the first year after childbirth. The cause is unknown. Hormonal and physical changes after birth and the stress of caring for a new baby may play a role. &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt; who have had depression are at higher risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think you have postpartum depression, tell your &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care provider. Medicines, including antidepressants, and talk therapy can help you get well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dept. of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Depression, Postpartum</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="groupName">Mental &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Behavior</content>
      <content name="groupName">Pregnancy and Reproduction</content>
      <content name="snippet"> ... of &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt; and Human Services Office on &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Women's&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;</content>
    </document>
    <document rank="9" url="https://medlineplus.gov/complementaryandintegrativemedicine.html">
      <content name="title">Complementary and Integrative Medicine</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Alternative Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">CAM</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Homeopathy</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Integrative Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">&lt;p&gt;Many Americans use medical treatments that are not part of mainstream medicine. When you are using these types of care, it may be called complementary, integrative, or alternative medicine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Complementary medicine is used together with mainstream medical care. An example is using acupuncture to help with side effects of cancer treatment. When &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; care providers and facilities offer both types of care, it is called integrative medicine. Alternative medicine is used instead of mainstream medical care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The claims that non-mainstream practitioners make can sound promising. However, researchers do not know how safe many of these treatments are or how well they work. Studies are underway to determine the safety and usefulness of many of these practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To minimize the &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;health&lt;/span&gt; risks of a non-mainstream treatment:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Discuss it with your doctor. It might have side effects or interact with other medicines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find out what the research says about it&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose practitioners carefully&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tell all of your doctors and practitioners about all of the different types of treatments you use&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Center for Complementary and Integrative &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Health&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Complementary Therapies</content>
      <content name="groupName">&lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Wellness&lt;/span&gt; and Lifestyle</content>
      <content name="groupName">Complementary and Alternative Therapies</content>
      <content name="snippet"> Many Americans use medical treatments that are not part of mainstream medicine. When you are using these types of care, it may be called complementary, integrative,  ... </content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
